Will R. Warner

Memphis, TN | 901-292-6465 | will.r.warner@gmail.com | willrwarner.com

Professional Summary

Full-stack web developer with over 2 years of experience working in the IT industry and 8 years of experience in the Mechanical Engineering field in multiple industries. Skilled at working in teams and utilizing problem solving and time management abilities to deliver results in a safe, timely, and effective manner. Seeking a full-time web development position that will provide new experiences to grow my programming and project management abilities.

Related Skills

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Java, Java Spring Boot, and Oracle SQL
- Deploying applications to Unix servers
- Configuring and managing Jenkins build servers
- Utilizing SonarQube for code quality
- Controlling source code with GitHub and Subversion

Education

Tech901 - Web Programming

April 2019

Mississippi State University - Bachelor of Science - Mechanical Engineering Overall GPA: 4.0

December 2012

Overum Giri. 1.

Experience

Front-End Developer - The Nerdery, LLC - Remote

2021-Present

- Worked with clients to maintain and update Angular applications and libraries
- Upgraded Angular and TypeScript versions
- Troubleshot issues with internal library usage
- Assisted users with consumption of internal libraries
- Integrated monitoring tools into Angular applications

Full Stack Developer - ECS Federal, LLC. - Memphis, TN

2019-2021

- Lead development and deployment efforts for internal USPS web applications utilizing Angular, Java, and SQL
- Worked with internal and external customers and teams to resolve issues and ensure successful coordination between related applications
- Deployed applications to Unix environments working closely with DevOps and DBAs
- Migrated version controls systems from Subversion to GitHub
- Established Jenkins configurations to automate application builds to minimize manual build errors
- Utilized SonarQube to improve code quality
- Supervised and mentored an intern to ensure they were productive while also learning web development fundamentals

Mechanical Project Engineer - Diversified Conveyors, Intl. - Memphis, TN

2016-2019

- Performed as Lead Engineer and oversaw 5 junior engineers on a \$400 million project
- Worked with structural engineering firms to ensure adequate and compatible structural designs
- Coordinated with Project Management to ensure deliverables were completed on time and in accordance with the contract specifications and applicable codes
- Developed new drafting techniques to improve coordination with external vendors

Mechanical Design Engineer - Chevron Corporation - Richmond, CA

2013-2016

- Performed as Lead Engineer and supervised junior engineers for 2 plant outages with a total expenditure of \$23 million
- Optimized work scope on a project to reduce installation costs by \$20,000
- Worked with Materials Engineers to specify material requirements for equipment
- Analyzed inspections and test data with Inspectors and Technicians to develop repair plans

Mechanical Reliability Intern - Valero Energy Corporation - Memphis, TN

Summer 2012

- Worked with senior engineers to develop plans for refinery equipment upgrades
- Developed a database for tracking refinery equipment

Mechanical Engineering Co-op - Hunter Engineering Co. - Durant, MS

2010-2011

- Worked with senior engineers on quality control issues and factory upgrades
- Created a database for quality control inspection equipment
- Determined root causes of manufacturing issues and developed solutions to these issues